<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<indexing>
 <object alt="" name="Image3" object_type="graphic"/>
 <object alt="" name="Image11" object_type="graphic"/>
 <object alt="" name="Image8" object_type="graphic"/>
 <object alt="" name="Image7" object_type="graphic"/>
 <object alt="" name="Picture 5" object_type="graphic"/>
 <object alt="" name="Image9" object_type="graphic"/>
 <object alt="" name="Image1" object_type="graphic"/>
 <object alt="" name="Image2" object_type="graphic"/>
 <object alt="" name="Image10" object_type="graphic"/>
 <object alt="" name="Picture 15" object_type="graphic"/>
 <object alt="" name="Image4" object_type="graphic"/>
 <object alt="" name="Image5" object_type="graphic"/>
 <object alt="" name="Image6" object_type="graphic"/>
 <paragraph index="52" node_type="writer">CC:</paragraph>
 <paragraph index="53" node_type="writer">Florida - Senate Bill 7054 (S7054) </paragraph>
 <paragraph index="54" node_type="writer">   Rep. Wyman Duggan</paragraph>
 <paragraph index="55" node_type="writer">   Sen Jim Boyd</paragraph>
 <paragraph index="56" node_type="writer">   Senator Nick DiCeglie</paragraph>
 <paragraph index="58" node_type="writer">Indiana - Senate Bill 468 (SB468)</paragraph>
 <paragraph index="59" node_type="writer">   Sen. Chris Garten</paragraph>
 <paragraph index="60" node_type="writer">   Senator Eric Koch</paragraph>
 <paragraph index="61" node_type="writer">   Senator Greg Taylor</paragraph>
 <paragraph index="63" node_type="writer">Alabama - Senate bill SB330</paragraph>
 <paragraph index="64" node_type="writer">   Sen. Dan Roberts</paragraph>
 <paragraph index="66" node_type="writer">North Dakota - Senate Bill 2392</paragraph>
 <paragraph index="67" node_type="writer">   Senator Bob Paulson</paragraph>
 <paragraph index="68" node_type="writer">   Senator Judy Estenson	</paragraph>
 <paragraph index="69" node_type="writer">   Senator Mike Wobbema	</paragraph>
 <paragraph index="71" node_type="writer">South Dakota - House Bill 1193</paragraph>
 <paragraph index="72" node_type="writer">   Rep Mike Stevens</paragraph>
 <paragraph index="73" node_type="writer">   Rep Hugh M. Bartels</paragraph>
 <paragraph index="74" node_type="writer">   Rep David Kull</paragraph>
 <paragraph index="75" node_type="writer">   Rep Carl E. Perry</paragraph>
 <paragraph index="77" node_type="writer">Louisiana - HB 415</paragraph>
 <paragraph index="78" node_type="writer">   Beryl A. Amedée</paragraph>
 <paragraph index="79" node_type="writer">   Paula P. Davis</paragraph>
 <paragraph index="80" node_type="writer">   Stephanie Hilferty</paragraph>
 <paragraph index="81" node_type="writer">   </paragraph>
 <paragraph index="82" node_type="writer">North Carolina (H721)</paragraph>
 <paragraph index="83" node_type="writer">   Rep. Mark Brody</paragraph>
 <paragraph index="84" node_type="writer">   Rep. Harry Warren</paragraph>
 <paragraph index="86" node_type="writer">GOLD DIGR White Paper – 2024, Ver 5</paragraph>
 <paragraph index="87" node_type="writer">Broward Horne, Tallahassee, FL</paragraph>
 <paragraph index="88" node_type="writer">browardhorne@gmail.com</paragraph>
 <paragraph index="89" node_type="writer">https://broward.ghost.io/tag/gold-currency/</paragraph>
 <paragraph index="90" node_type="writer">
</paragraph>
 <paragraph index="91" node_type="writer">I'm a software developer with 35 years of experience. I believe there may soon be demand from State governments for R&amp;D, prototyping and development of gold-backed digital currencies as described in Texas bills S.B. No. 2334 and H.B. No. 4903. </paragraph>
 <paragraph index="92" node_type="writer">Abstract:</paragraph>
 <paragraph index="93" node_type="writer">This paper contains three complementary proposals to create a digital currency backed by a State-regulated depository like the Texas Bullion Depository established in 2015.  The first proposal is the currency itself including history, justification and legislation‚ the second is a development strategy‚ the third adds flexible exchange rates between participating States.</paragraph>
 <paragraph index="95" node_type="writer">1) GOLD DIGR is an overview of a State-regulated digital currency necessitated by historical and political forces‚ current legislation and strategic design.</paragraph>
 <paragraph index="97" node_type="writer">2) TWG proposes a multi-State committee to develop a standard currency framework adaptable to multiple States and external partners.</paragraph>
 <paragraph index="99" node_type="writer">3) SXS is an interstate currency exchange system similar to the BRICS attempt to displace the Federal Reserve’s centralized system.</paragraph>
 <paragraph index="101" node_type="writer">My goal with these mailings is to make this into a real system via State funding‚ grants‚ consulting contracts, corporate sponsorship. etc.  I’ve had an ongoing interest in this since 1994, I believe in it and have the skill and knowledge to make happen.  My background is eclectic and spans startups‚ corporations‚ State and Federal systems for 35 years.</paragraph>
 <paragraph index="106" node_type="writer">Historical Background </paragraph>
 <paragraph index="107" node_type="writer">This current period of fiat currency has already lasted longer than previous fiats of the past several hundred years and contrary forces are aligning to end it. Russia and China have planned for the end of the fiat dollar for the past fifteen years, the US dollar is ripe for replacement as the world reserve currency, and the current Federal debt is unsustainable.</paragraph>
 <paragraph index="108" node_type="writer">Gold Standard</paragraph>
 <paragraph index="109" node_type="writer">The longest period in modern history without a gold standard is now; from 1971 to 2024 or 53 years. The last major gold standard system was the Bretton Woods system, which operated from 1944 to 1971. The United States has abandoned its gold standard in unusual situations (Civil war, World War 1, etc) but only briefly.</paragraph>
 <paragraph index="110" node_type="writer">Russian Gold Reserves</paragraph>
 <paragraph index="111" node_type="writer">Russia's central bank has steadily increased gold reserves since 2009 to diversify from the dollar and foreign currencies. Russia's gold reserves tripled from 600 metric tons in 2009 to over 2,300 metric tons in early 2021.</paragraph>
 <paragraph index="112" node_type="writer">Chinese Gold Reserves</paragraph>
 <paragraph index="113" node_type="writer">China has consistently increased gold reserves since 2009 to diversify away from dollars and foreign currencies, and China's gold reserves grew from 1,054 metric tons in 2009 to over 1,948 metric tons in early 2021.</paragraph>
 <paragraph index="114" node_type="writer">Hegemony</paragraph>
 <paragraph index="115" node_type="writer">Western hegemonic empires since 1400 A.D. had an average lifespan of 95 years and the United States has already exceeded that. The world reserve currency is usually a function of the current hegemony. </paragraph>
 <paragraph index="117" node_type="writer">Interest Payments</paragraph>
 <paragraph index="118" node_type="writer">The current rate of increase in Federal debt interest payments is unsustainable.</paragraph>
 <paragraph index="120" node_type="writer">Interest Rates</paragraph>
 <paragraph index="121" node_type="writer">As debt increases, rates must fall to maintain equilibrium. Interest rates during the credit upcycle (1980 to 2020) have fallen as far as investors will tolerate. This return of higher rates will be disastrous for the current debt.</paragraph>
 <paragraph index="122" node_type="writer">BRICS Strategy</paragraph>
 <paragraph index="123" node_type="writer">De-dollarization. The BRICS separate financial system aims to use their oligopoly power to control commodity prices and bypass the US Dollar. BRICS countries control 50% of the world's food supply, 70% of the microchip supply (China + Taiwan) and enough energy to control pricing in concert with a partner like Saudi Arabia or Venezuela.</paragraph>
 <paragraph index="126" node_type="writer">USA Legislation</paragraph>
 <paragraph index="127" node_type="writer">The Sound Money Movement is a political and economic movement that advocates for a stable, reliable currency and believes central banks should not manipulate currencies for political gain and that a gold or silver-based currency would provide greater stability. The movement supports precious metal legislation across the United States.</paragraph>
 <paragraph index="128" node_type="writer">Three-Step Legislative Strategy</paragraph>
 <paragraph index="129" node_type="writer">Pass legislation to legalize gold and silver</paragraph>
 <paragraph index="130" node_type="writer">Create a State-controlled precious metals repository</paragraph>
 <paragraph index="131" node_type="writer">Create a digital token currency backed by the repository</paragraph>
 <paragraph index="133" node_type="writer">1) States where gold and silver are legal tender</paragraph>
 <paragraph index="136" node_type="writer"> </paragraph>
 <paragraph index="153" node_type="writer">2) Previous States plus States with pending legislation</paragraph>
 <paragraph index="155" node_type="writer">Previous Depository Legislation</paragraph>
 <paragraph index="156" node_type="writer">Texas Bullion Depository Bill - signed into law in 2015 to create a state bullion depository.</paragraph>
 <paragraph index="157" node_type="writer">2023: Tennessee Bullion Depository Act - SB 150 to establish a precious metals depository.</paragraph>
 <paragraph index="158" node_type="writer">2023: Mississippi SB2966 - establish the Mississippi bullion depository</paragraph>
 <paragraph index="159" node_type="writer">2023: Missouri HB718 - create the “Missouri Bullion Depository.”</paragraph>
 <paragraph index="160" node_type="writer">2023: North Carolina H721 - State Precious Metals Depository Study</paragraph>
 <paragraph index="161" node_type="writer">2023: Idaho H0180 - invest in precious metals held in a secure depository</paragraph>
 <paragraph index="162" node_type="writer">2023: Oklahoma SB 816 - Establish a State Treasury Depository</paragraph>
 <paragraph index="163" node_type="writer">2023: Montana HB0884 - Department of Revenue authorizes a media of exchange using gold</paragraph>
 <paragraph index="165" node_type="writer">Impedance-Matched Currency</paragraph>
 <paragraph index="166" node_type="writer">Creating the Euro was somewhat like harnessing a horse, a mule, a dog and a turtle to pull a wagon. A &quot;one size fits all&quot; strategy creates stresses because regions (States) have different resources, skill levels, goals. Most economic transactions are local and a State currency would be controlled regionally.</paragraph>
 <paragraph index="167" node_type="writer">
</paragraph>
 <paragraph index="168" node_type="writer">GOLD DIGR Proposal </paragraph>
 <paragraph index="169" node_type="writer">This is an abstract high-level diagram of how a gold-backed digital currency would work. </paragraph>
 <paragraph index="170" node_type="writer">A more detailed design is at https://broward.ghost.io/golddigr/tactical</paragraph>
 <paragraph index="172" node_type="writer">Depository: stores gold deposits.
Inventory System: manages gold deposits
Currency: manages cash transactions
Blockchain: equivalent to accounting ledger
Key Manager: equivalent to safety deposit box keys
Client: Customer with gold in depository</paragraph>
 <paragraph index="175" node_type="writer">Assumptions: An existing depository has an existing inventory management system. That system needs to synchronize with the blockchain entries. </paragraph>
 <paragraph index="177" node_type="writer">Low Energy Use:</paragraph>
 <paragraph index="178" node_type="writer">GOLD DIGR won’t require enormous energy. It should consume the same energy as sending an email or editing a document. Most crypto-currencies refer to &quot;mining” which uses energy-intensive functions to create artificial scarcity. GOLD DIGR's scarcity is the gold depository itself</paragraph>
 <paragraph index="179" node_type="writer">Low Complexity:</paragraph>
 <paragraph index="180" node_type="writer">GOLD DIGR is less complex than crypto-currencies. It doesn't require &quot;proof&quot; schemes to generate scarcity, validation and consensus mechanisms, etc.</paragraph>
 <paragraph index="183" node_type="writer">Sending A Transaction</paragraph>
 <paragraph index="185" node_type="writer">1. Client sends a transaction to Currency API</paragraph>
 <paragraph index="187" node_type="writer">Example message:</paragraph>
 <paragraph index="189" node_type="writer">{  </paragraph>
 <paragraph index="190" node_type="writer">    &quot;message&quot;: {  </paragraph>
 <paragraph index="191" node_type="writer">        &quot;message_type&quot;: &quot;texas_transaction&quot;,</paragraph>
 <paragraph index="192" node_type="writer">        &quot;version&quot;: 1.12,</paragraph>
 <paragraph index="193" node_type="writer">        &quot;date&quot;: &quot;2024-02-03T06:48:07&quot;,</paragraph>
 <paragraph index="194" node_type="writer">        &quot;ID&quot;: 010102283,</paragraph>
 <paragraph index="195" node_type="writer">        &quot;payer&quot;:  12221,   </paragraph>
 <paragraph index="196" node_type="writer">        &quot;payee&quot;: 1023,   </paragraph>
 <paragraph index="197" node_type="writer">        &quot;amount&quot;: &quot;$100&quot;</paragraph>
 <paragraph index="198" node_type="writer">    }  </paragraph>
 <paragraph index="199" node_type="writer">}  </paragraph>
 <paragraph index="201" node_type="writer">2. Currency forwards message to Key Manager.</paragraph>
 <paragraph index="203" node_type="writer">3. Key Manager verifies the payer, payee and payer’s balance.</paragraph>
 <paragraph index="205" node_type="writer">4. Key Manager creates blockchain entry and sends result to Currency.</paragraph>
 <paragraph index="207" node_type="writer">5. Currency sends result to client.</paragraph>
 <paragraph index="209" node_type="writer">A much more detailed design is at https://broward.ghost.io/golddigr/tactical
More information on AWS implementation</paragraph>
 <paragraph index="214" node_type="writer">
</paragraph>
 <paragraph index="216" node_type="writer">TWG Proposal (Technical Working Group) </paragraph>
 <paragraph index="217" node_type="writer">Recent legislation shows significant interest in Texas-style precious metal depositories. This proposal is for a Technical Working Group (TWG) of interested parties to fund joint development of regional depositories with common procedures and a digital currency platform. Here's an example.</paragraph>
 <paragraph index="221" node_type="writer">We used this model at Federal Highway from 1994 to 1996 to develop ASPEN, CDLIS and ISS software with a permanent staff of five. Ten States contributed 1-2 members each quarter for a three-day design and feedback meeting (about 500 man hours annually).</paragraph>
 <paragraph index="222" node_type="writer">5 Major Components</paragraph>
 <paragraph index="223" node_type="writer">1) Development Group - Independent organization which combines input to produce policies, protocols and platform for State depositories.</paragraph>
 <paragraph index="225" node_type="writer">2) Technical Working Group (TWG) - a steering committee of States which contribute funding, feedback and policies from part-time advisors in each State.</paragraph>
 <paragraph index="227" node_type="writer">3) Regional Depositories - State depositories which support digital currencies and interoperate with other depositories.</paragraph>
 <paragraph index="229" node_type="writer">4) Savings Institutions - contribute funding to use the State depositories and currencies as a mechanism of investment and wealth preservation.</paragraph>
 <paragraph index="231" node_type="writer">5) Commercial Industry - retail vendors, 3rd party developers to support digital currencies.</paragraph>
 <paragraph index="233" node_type="writer">SXS Proposal (State Exchange System) </paragraph>
 <paragraph index="234" node_type="writer">
The SXS platform has three functions.</paragraph>
 <paragraph index="236" node_type="writer">Manage financial transactions between platform members</paragraph>
 <paragraph index="237" node_type="writer">Collect information to calculate real-time exchange rates</paragraph>
 <paragraph index="238" node_type="writer">Adjust foreign reserves pools between platform members</paragraph>
 <paragraph index="241" node_type="writer">CENTRALIZED 
This is the design of the Federal Reserve and the realms represent countries and States. It’s inflexible but efficient and scalable with a single point of control and authority (hub). Over 100 countries use it.</paragraph>
 <paragraph index="243" node_type="writer">POINT-TO-POINT (PTP)
The BRICS countries are creating a point-to-point system which is less efficient but has more flexibility and freedom.  Different rates are possible between Realm1 to Realm2 and Realm1 to Realm3, etc.</paragraph>
 <paragraph index="247" node_type="writer">In the PTP system, a visitor regularly converses with all realms and executes a common set of functions.  Within each realm are pending transactions, current exchange rates, foreign reserve pools.  The visitor executes transactions, recalculates exchange rates and balances foreign reserve pools.  Exchange rates are determining by the relationship between two realms instead of a central authority and each country (State) has some control in the exchange rate for each trading partner.</paragraph>
 <paragraph index="249" node_type="writer">Here is a small working software model of SXS (https://github.com/broward/BRICS)</paragraph>
 <paragraph index="250" node_type="writer">More detailed model  (https://broward.ghost.io/BRICS)</paragraph>
 <paragraph index="251" node_type="writer">Author </paragraph>
 <paragraph index="252" node_type="writer">Thirty-five years of eclectic software development, including seven startups, IT staff at a major university, several USDOT grants and fifteen years of corporate consulting. Three DEFCON presentations on predictive analytics.</paragraph>
 <paragraph index="253" node_type="writer">State governments</paragraph>
 <paragraph index="254" node_type="writer">From 1991-1996, I was the original architect in several Federal Highway Administration grants developing the first handheld and wireless systems (ASPEN, CDLIS, ISS) for State-level motor carrier inspections. I led a quarterly design conference with representatives from ten States to define features and recommendations and worked directly with State managers, IT staff and police officers, often on-site. We achieved a 40-State adoption of this software.</paragraph>
 <paragraph index="255" node_type="writer">Digital Currencies</paragraph>
 <paragraph index="256" node_type="writer">Hands-on work with three currencies - the Digital Money Trust in 1994 (a precursor to Bitcoin), an IoT token prototype in 2014 and Sila stablecoin in 2018 which received $21 million in venture capital. I developed the MVP (minimum viable product) in 100 days and we used it in 50 demonstrations for funding. I designed and wrote about 75% of the original beta release code, API, security.</paragraph>
 <paragraph index="257" node_type="writer">Contracting</paragraph>
 <paragraph index="258" node_type="writer">Significant projects at Boeing (call center), Avnet (e-commerce), Aetna (case management), Amdocs (payment system), DLVR.com (video analytics), Verizon (ring tone sales), Staples (e-commerce). Many run one million+ transactions per day and had requirements for internal integrations, adapters and legacy limitations, etc.</paragraph>
 <paragraph index="259" node_type="writer">DEFCON</paragraph>
 <paragraph index="260" node_type="writer">Three DEFCON convention presentations in 2005-2007 on predictive analytics and memetic manipulations such as election hacking.</paragraph>
 <paragraph index="261" node_type="writer">Related Materal By Me</paragraph>
 <paragraph index="262" node_type="writer">Texas Depository, 2023 (https://broward.ghost.io/texas_depo)</paragraph>
 <paragraph index="263" node_type="writer">BRICS Currency System, 2023 (https://broward.ghost.io/BRICS)</paragraph>
 <paragraph index="264" node_type="writer">AWS App Design, 2023 (https://broward.ghost.io/aws_app_1)</paragraph>
 <paragraph index="265" node_type="writer">Stablecoin Hack, 2022 (https://broward.ghost.io/stablecoin_hack)</paragraph>
 <paragraph index="266" node_type="writer">Miner Bankruptcy, 2022 (https://broward.ghost.io/miner_bankruptcy)</paragraph>
 <paragraph index="267" node_type="writer">Polymorphic API, 2022 (https://broward.ghost.io/polymorphic_api/)</paragraph>
 <paragraph index="268" node_type="writer">Crypto Platform, 2020 (https://broward.ghost.io/crypto_platform)</paragraph>
 <paragraph index="269" node_type="writer">Payment System, 2015 (https://broward.ghost.io/payment_system)</paragraph>
 <paragraph index="270" node_type="writer">Bitcoin Scalability, 2015 (https://broward.ghost.io/bitcoin_scalability)</paragraph>
 <paragraph index="271" node_type="writer">Digital Money Trust, 2015 (https://broward.ghost.io/digital_money_trust)</paragraph>
 <paragraph index="272" node_type="writer">Jing Currency on IoT, 2014 (https://broward.ghost.io/digital_on_IoT)</paragraph>
 <paragraph index="273" node_type="writer">Aetna Migration, 2011 (https://broward.ghost.io/aetna)</paragraph>
 <paragraph index="274" node_type="writer">Avnet E-commerce, 2000 (https://broward.ghost.io/avnet)</paragraph>
 <paragraph index="275" node_type="writer">Multi-Tenant Systems, 1996-2018 (https://broward.ghost.io/multi-tenant)</paragraph>
 <paragraph index="276" node_type="writer">Federal Highway System, 1992-1996 (https://broward.ghost.io/FHWA/)</paragraph>
 <paragraph index="277" node_type="writer">Hacking the Planet, 1988 (https://broward.ghost.io/hack_the_planet)</paragraph>
</indexing>
